We've looked at the data of 3,000
venture capital firms in the US. Only 20
have achieved consistent 3x net returns
over the last two decades.
>> Right now, clearly the power law is more
extreme than it has been in the last 10
to 20 years of technology investing. For
the first time, you can take capital and
throw it at a company and it compounds
their advantage.
>> AI is attacking every facet of the GDP,
transportation, labor, services,
capital, coordination. There hasn't been
a technology paradigm that hits on 30
trillion in GDP at the same Elon has
talked publicly about Grockbot on Sam's
side. He's talked about Astra and some
of the longrunning capabilities that are
going to come out soon.
>> What do you think is going to be the
next hundred trillion dollar market cap
company?
>> It is possible that
Welcome back to the A16Z podcast.
Something fundamental has changed in how
value gets created. Power law used to be
just a feature of a cottage industry in
venture capital and now it's systemic
throughout and particularly the three
frontier model companies SpaceX, OpenAI,
Anthropic represent somewhere between
three and a half to 5 trillion dollars
of potential enterprise value. And
shockingly before SpaceX went public, a
lot of our LPs and also the broader
institutional allocator community didn't
have a lot of exposure to it. And so
we'll talk about today why uh
potentially portfolio construction and
asset allocation may have changed um why
power law is not just only in the
venture capital industry and then
particularly where and how value
actually compounds today. David George
around Verdian thank you for joining me.
>> Great to be here. Thanks for hanging
out.
>> Thank you for having us here.
>> Awesome. Awesome. Awesome. Okay. So DG.
So if you add up every venturebacked IPO
for the last six years, all of them
together, where does it go from here?
Right now clearly the power law is more
extreme than it has been in the last you
know 10 to 20 years of technology
investing probably going back to you
know the emergence of the network effect
driven consumer companies. Um there are
many reasons why that's the case.
Increasing returns to scale have always
been a dynamic in our business.
Obviously it's well covered how a
network effect business can have
increasing returns to scale but so can
software businesses right and and they
can take different forms but you know
brand reputation in the market the
accumulation of resources all provide
competitive advantages that all still is
the case but right now especially with
the labs for the first time you know in
my career you can take capital and throw
it at a company and it compounds their
advantage and this is a thing like how
do you screw up a a startup, um well,
you know, throw too much money at it and
have them hire a thousand people and
then, you know, you create all these
coordination issues and overhead issues
and and dueling priorities and and it
sort of gets messed up because you can't
hire enough people to do enough things
fast enough. Um, now that's not the
case. You can throw dollars at compute
and compute can make products and the
businesses better. And so to me, it's
not terribly surprising that the power
law is more extreme. Right now,
economies of scale are a very real thing
uh in the AI market. and I think will
continue to be the case.
>> So, Ron, so first of all, uh you're not
just one of our longtime LPs at
accolade, uh but incidentally, it's been
exactly 10 years since you were actually
an employee of A16Z. And so, for your 10
year anniversary, since you were last
year, I've brought this gem back.
>> Oh my god. Oh my gosh. This is amazing.
Why do you still have this? This is
amazing.
>> So, we dug in the catacombs uh and we
made this extra large version uh just
for for posterity here. I can't believe
that I got this from the from the
catacombs. But incidentally, during the
last 10 years, a lot has changed in the
world. And and if you remember, at that
point in time, people were belly aching
about fund sizes being too large back
then.
>> And you had one at a billion. I remember
>> the the first one out of billion. First
venture fund. Exactly. Exactly. And so,
you know, a lot has happened since then.
How do you think about your venture
portfolio juxtaposed against your
private equity one? And then just also
generally asset allocation. We were
talking about this on the way in. If you
were to start from a blank sheet of
paper again knowing what you know now,
how would you have constructed
differently?
>> Yeah, let's take venture today. We've
reached 100 billion in revenue in AI. It
took SAS 15 years to get to the same
point. AI did that in four years and
we're not even close to anywhere in
terms of the penetration of demand. The
reason DG is saying you can throw
capital at it the fun that's a function
of unlimited demand for inference and we
are at a point where AI is attacking
every facet of the GDP transportation
labor services capital coordination
there hasn't been a technology paradigm
that hits on 30 trillion in GDP at the
same time and so you have the fastest
growing technology it's hitting on all
parts of the GDP so as an allocator it's
hard not to make the case, you should
it's not a satellite position. You
should be core or a super core in some
shape or form.
>> I'm very biased, but if you just think
about the the shape of the markets and
how they've changed since I started my
career, um you know, in private equity
and growth equity, you know, that was I
guess 18 years ago. This was a cottage
industry and now it's not. And I talk
about this all the time, but our asset
class is 5 to6 trillion dollars of
value. and the dynamics around companies
staying private longer, they're not
going to reverse.
>> Yeah. I mean, you had that insight in
2019 when you left G. It's venture- like
outcomes in late stage, which is now
happening. Like,
>> so it's no longer just early stage and
you IPO when you have 100 million in
revenues.
>> Yeah. The top desk outcomes, I think,
used to be 10 billion and now they're
like 40 billion.
>> Yeah. Or soon to be probably 100 billion
by the time anthropic and then open AI
came come out. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And look, this makes
sense, right? Like the last cycle
created 25 trillion of market cap, new
market cap and a bunch of that went to
the incumbents.
>> Y
>> but a lot of it went to to startups and
the new startups and you know each one
of these subsequent waves gets bigger
than the prior one. And so
>> you know our expectation is you know
that take the 25 trillion and like it's
going to be a larger number.
>> Yep.
>> Yeah. And I'm
constantly confused about the TAM of AI.
We'll love your thoughts on this. Um
like take healthcare. Healthcare spends
like 60 to 100 billion on healthcare it
per year. But AI is hitting on actual
labor and the value of tasks that are
being performed in healthcare. That's
claims, billing, administration. That's
a trillion dollar industry. So the TAM
of AI can be 10x plus bigger than
traditional SAS or healthcare IT. And
what is that value? Well, what's the
economic value of a task that's being
performed like that's the TAM you're
looking at. And then there's some
capture rate that the AI company will
take. But we have no idea what how big
the TAM can get. to your point, it's you
look at every wave, the incumbents are
10x smaller uh over time. So, it's hard
to estimate it, but I can tell this for
myself. I've been chronically wrong
about how big these outcomes can get.
>> Yeah, same here. Yeah, labor. I mean,
look, if you just look at like how much
of, you know, dollars are spent in the
US economy on labor versus software,
it's like something like 40 times more.
Now, that doesn't mean importantly that
um labor is going to go away. Like I
think labor is just going to get
reinvented and so we'll we'll end up
with um you know sort of reimagination
of the task that humans do. Um but I
think that's actually the the the whole
point of AI is like you're going after
this different thing. And so to equate
it to software and say oh it's the next
evolution of software is far too
limiting.
>> Our legal council uh says to us often
it's like I love Harvey. All my clients
think they're lawyers now and they could
actually spar with me on topics where
they would have probably been like I
don't really understand this. I'm just
going to defer to you. So my billable
hours have only gone up with the advent
of the usage of AI. And so all those use
cases are are massively massively um
probably underappreciated and we don't
still even know
>> they're expansionary. Yeah. Is the whole
point. Yeah.
>> And then there was there was this whole
thesis where well Frontier Labs are
going to cannibise the apps which layer
is going to win. Turns out like everyone
is sort of growing.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. We just um you know a
friend of mine did a podcast where he
described like everything is going to
work kind of thing. Mhm.
>> Um, and um, you know, I I describe it
slightly differently, but it's like, you
know, we get questions all the time from
LPs when they ask us like,
>> you know, layer in the stack,
>> which layer in the stack is going to
work. And I'm kind of like, I don't
know, the the market is going to be so
big. Like, I think everything might
work. Now, there's going to be a lot of
companies that don't work and there may
be idiosyncratic categories that don't
work. Um, but I think by and large, it's
far too limiting to think like, oh, if
open source does a good job, it's bad
for the labs and, you know, vice versa.
Uh so we try and like remove ourselves
from thinking in a zero sum way like
that.
>> Yeah.
>> Extract it out because why why do people
think it's going to be a winner or take
all and and you know if we can
hypothesize but you know the last era of
technology it was probably winner take
all in a lot of categories but this
feels categorically different because
we're reunderwiting a lot of the
fundamentals. So maybe extract it out.
Yeah, look, winner take all is an
interesting way to describe it because
like if you just look at the market cap
growth of all the leading technology
companies like there are many many many
that were successful like there wasn't
winner take all right now there's an
important distinction like we very much
are believers in the power law within a
given category so like the winners will
capture the vast majority of the market
share um and market cap and second place
is like playing for scraps you know um
>> uh but I think there will see a massive
expansion of the amount of categories
that we have, right? And so, you know,
if you go back 20 years like CRM was not
really a category I mean it was small.
It was like seable systems and and
things like that. Um but you know now
it's a massive category. And so I think
the same thing will happen. We've seen
it in every technology market that we
invest in. Again, our approach is um you
know in our business we can tolerate
loss, right? And like if we're not
losing money in a given fund on a given
amount of investments, we're not taking
enough risk, right? And so, you know, if
you look at our best performing venture
funds over time, I think the loss rate
is 60%. Yeah.
>> Or so
>> on early stage. Yeah.
>> On early stage. Um, now at the growth
stage, like the loss rate will be lower,
but it's probably going to be in the 10
to 20% range. And that's appropriate
because
>> with that, you will get investments that
we make that, you know, 10x or more in
returns. And so, um, you know, if we're
doing a good job, we're backing the
leading company in every category that
is a credible category. And if the
category works out well, then we do a
great job. And if the category doesn't
work out well, that's okay. That's kind
of like the risk that we live with.
>> Yeah. Yep. Yep. And and embedded in that
is also kind of timing because I I know
around you and I lament on this in that
I think a lot of folks often times think
that things are overheated in that
moment in time and then you look back in
retrospect and it turns out everything
was actually quite cheap but then
there's these aberrations in the market
where it's probably actually true and so
I know you advise a lot of your LPs on
on the cons importance of consistency in
venture capital probably even more than
any other asset class because you just
never know when these technologies can
come out. maybe walk through that
because there's a lot of institutional
allocators out there who actually don't
have access to a lot of the frontier
certainly models now. They're trying to
play catch-up and and in some instances
probably maybe introducing some adverse
behavior that is a little bit too
reflective of things being a little bit
too frothy. So maybe unpack that for us.
>> Yeah, I mean the extreness of the power
law that DG talked about. If you as an
allocator have not had access to the top
5 to 10 companies over the last 5 to 10
years, you're significantly behind in
terms of returns. And let's take a step
back. Like we've looked at the data of
3,000 venture capital firms in the US.
Only 20 have achieved consistent 3x net
returns over the last two decades.
>> Sorry, say that one more. 20% have 20
>> less than 1%.
>> Wow.
>> Consistent 3x net returns.
>> That's incredible. And it's actually you
don't have you don't need seven eight
funds in those 20 years. Are it was do
you have three to four 3x net TVPI funds
over a 20-year period. We found only 20
>> firms that have done that.
>> Wow.
>> Consistency in venture is really really
hard.
>> But what's interesting is the consistent
ones
>> consistently had access to the category
defining companies every vintage.
>> Yeah.
>> Um now there are exceptions and by the
way just having the logo is not
sufficient enough. If you're early stage
and you have a large fund, you need to
own enough of it.
>> If you're late stage, DJ, I'm curious if
you agree, sizing is really critical.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh so venture- like returns are possible
in late stage, but your best company
should be 5 10% plus of your fund. That
way you can actually return the fund on
a single company. Fund returning math in
late stage didn't exist before. It now
does.
>> Yeah.
>> Um so we have found the right portfolio
sizing and the ones that consistently
have gotten access are in that top 20
out of 3,000. So if you don't have them,
there's a huge dispersion of returns.
And if you don't have those, you're
getting the average venture return. If
you look at Cambridge data, the average
venture return over the last 10 years is
1 to 2x.
>> You'll do better in private equity.
You'll definitely do better in the
public markets. You don't need to lock
up your money for 10 years.
>> Yeah, for sure. Yeah. I I just pulled up
a tweet uh from our friend Eddie who
posted actually this this morning. He
said, "Internest in big VC funds has
been driven by founders, not LPs.
Founders more often than not want the
brand that can scale, be a life cycle
investor, and help land customers/hires.
LPs have slowly followed along, but most
are still dragging their heels because
it actually it's counter to conventional
wisdom.
>> Yeah. And the outcomes are larger, so
funds can be larger. There are some
exceptions in those 20. There are some
small firms that are focused on niche
vertical markets
>> or they're playing at a stage that's so
much earlier than the bigger firms where
like there is not a lot of competition
with the bigger firms. Now the problem
with that strategy is you have to stay
consistent in terms of fund size and
their strategy. If you start getting
bigger over time then you bump into the
big firms and I think it it becomes
really really hard to stay consistent.
>> Yeah. Yep. Death of the middle.
>> Death of the middle of the middle.
>> We said we were going to drink every
time we said death of the middle. So
>> I'm very complimentary of of many of our
peers in the in the venture ecosystem.
Um you know like but this this death of
the middle thing
>> how do you define it?
>> Like what's the middle? Uh so I think
like sort of what you described like the
highly specialized funds you know some
of the ones that were very early to AI
with like deep deep deep domain experts
>> um have done a pretty good job right
like they've done a good job and and you
know sometimes they can move fast get
into things or take shares of deals that
we want to do and you know that that is
that is a reality um then I think
there's like the you know whatever we're
you know large you know large scale
venture right in theense is that we have
many product lines and we can scale all
the way from, you know, a seed all the
way through to when you go public. Um,
and I think we have some peers who
employ a similar strategy, right? And,
you know, there's I'd like to think that
we're the best, but there's there's a
few other folks who do that. Everything
else in between that, I think, struggles
to compete a little bit for the reasons
that Eddie said, right? The what does
the founder care about? the founder
cares about um you know sort of taking
capital from a partner that they think
can derisk the outcome for themselves
like that if you were just to simplify
it that is the simplest way to describe
what the founder really cares about. Now
they care about the partner, right? Like
the government person. So you have to
you have to be a good actor and all
those things. But there's a reason why
we build up a tremendous amount of
resources, right? Like that's why we
have 700 employees. Uh that's why we
take, you know, the management fees that
we make on our funds and we invest them
in operating resources because we think
that it will one bend the curve on the
outcome and two help us to win deals.
Um, and so, you know, when founders
select their partners often, you know,
if it's a hot deal, like they'll have
many alternatives. Like, that's the
revealed preference. And, and you know,
as Eddie said, we're doing an okay job
with that. What I agree with him about
then is our LPs coming to invest in us
is a byproduct of that, right? Um, and
so, you know, our business, our business
is a flywheel. Um, the flywheel starts
with um, you know, are we are we deep
domain experts? uh are we going to have
a point of view uh that is the right
point of view? Um can we demonstrate to
the founder that we you know are the
right partner for for her or him? Um if
so, we win the deal. If we can help to
make the outcome better, that's great.
Um and then if we do make the outcome
better, there's two things that happen.
One, um our business has persistence of
returns partially because um you know
the the new founder wants to be around
the winners, right? they want they care
about because there's important brand
and that has knock on effects for them.
Um and then secondly, you know, by being
a part of the winners and helping them,
you know, in small ways, uh we we create
sort of killer references and the
founders then tell the other founders,
hey, you should work with these folks.
And so that's the way the flywheel works
in our business.
>> One theory curious to get your both of
your takes is
>> take preed seats. So sub 20, 30, $40
million valuation, sub$und00 million
funds, they can coexist with the big
firms because at inception stage, say
there's seven AI companies kind of doing
the same thing. I would think a large
firm like Andre would want to wait for a
round or two until there's more relative
certainty because one thing you don't
want to do is be in the number two or
number three like you said, you have to
be in the category winner. So you rather
wait for that round and actually double
down and lead the A or the B. Mhm.
>> So the small firms, they can carve out a
niche for themselves a clip or two
earlier than the big firms and actually
have a right to win. They can do really
well and be complimentary to the big
firms.
>> Yeah.
>> Do you agree with that or like Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And look, we have like
very healthy relationships with with
seed funds across the ecosystem. Um we
also do do seed ourselves, right? But
preede for sure, you know, sort of
earlier than we typically.
>> The seed you would do I think is like
chunkier bigger seed, right? Like a
serial entrepreneur.
>> They used to be a Yeah.
>> Yeah. that that definitely is our that
said, you know, we have our speedrun
program which we just came from actually
earlier this uh this morning and I don't
know I think
>> I think the market is evolving where
we're where um because founders have
such a preferential attachment as as DG
was saying to the brands we get to look
at everything and sometimes it does make
sense for us to do the preede and seed
and so you know you kind of want that
flex of capability and for the founder
to your point they kind of don't really
care where your focus is they just want
to be in that orbit and like you'll find
the funds to kind of match to it and so
I think we can coexist in this world but
I I think it's also very um important
like our business is principally an
early stage business we have to be first
to the poll and we may not actually do
the investment but we have to at least
understand the landscape and market to
be able to actually make the informed
decisions later on and so
>> I spoke to a few founders at speedrun
today and they very much are hoping to
stay in the orbit
>> yeah long term right and so this is you
know a new phenomena that were 10 years
ago again this is starting to really
take shape as more of the early stage
folks started doing later stage and then
extending process stack but not quite in
the way that it is today and DJ I don't
know if you you would agree with that
like it's just virtually impossible to
have this sort of mid-stage business
effectively without having the early
stage and then also the late stage and
come behind it as well.
>> Yeah, I mean look I'm very biased uh but
I think the reason that we've been
successful as a growth fund is because
of our early stage business. I said that
all the time like our business starts
and ends with early stage and so um you
know that provides us a tremendous
amount of advantages at the growth stage
um in terms of access information,
knowledge um relationships etc. Um and I
would think that you know our early
stage partners would probably say that
the growth business provides them
benefits too because it allows you know
us to scale up and deepen partnerships
with founders over time and that helps
to win deals at the at the early stage.
>> Yeah. Totally. Totally. And you can't
there's both sides. You can't only do
the early, you can't also only wait till
the late too. And so your point earlier
around it looks like increasingly that
firms are converging to a handful of
names. Like that's probably true because
you know again this power law dynamic
but also at the same time almost
majority of those logos so to speak we
have to get at the early because that's
the only way we maintain the ball
control and also participate in the
prata and then some. And so that's
obviously the the business that
>> we're big believers that the strongest
latestage franchises have a huge early
stage franchise attached to them. Like
the ability to win is multiplied when
you have an early stage franchise. Yeah.
Like it's
>> um and we talked about sizing in late
stage where you can whatever the size of
your late stage fund is, if you can at
scale put 5 to 10% of your fund in one
of the category defining companies. The
way you could do that is because you had
an early stage franchise that developed
that relation with the entrepreneur and
the management team early on. It's
really hard to come in as a denovo late
stage firm and write a $500 million
check.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. No, it's very hard.
Yeah. Uh Ive I've I've lived that world.
>> How do you think about from the LPC how
venture is fundamentally
perhaps a structurally different job
than maybe when you started your career
also as well? And you know how do you
think about also asset allocation within
venture because there's actually
subasses within venture as you think
about portfolio construction as well.
Yeah, I mean there's I mean in a very
simplistic way there's in our mind
there's four ways to do venture preceded
seed so think sub 150 funds there's
thousand thousand close to 2,000 today
in the US alone
>> messy middle we talked about and then
there's a lot of firms there by the way
thousands of not thousands hundreds of
firms and then the big firms
>> and then dedicated late stage so there's
four ways to play it
>> um we have done the larger firms
>> for decades now we've done the seed
firms we've select effectively done a
few in the messy middle
>> and we haven't done dedicated late stage
for the reasons we talked about.
>> Um how is it changing? AI is actually
making our jobs harder than ever before.
>> Um it's making it harder because rounds
are larger
>> in general. They're faster.
The traction that's happening in the
industry is confusing. And here's why
it's confusing. You can have a company
I'm actually really curious to hear this
from you because we hear this a lot.
company comes out of Pick Your
Accelerator. I went from zero to five
million ARR in a month.
>> Yeah.
>> There's no renewal cycle yet on that
company.
>> Yeah.
>> And they're raising off of that traction
at huge multiples. And a lot of times
they're selling to each other in a
cohort potentially. And it's not even
ARR, but they're multiplying by 12. So,
but for every C for nine companies like
that, there's one really special one
that's doing a couple of million in ARR
actual ARR that has a huge valuation
that will go on to be the next cursor.
>> Yeah. So it is really really tough
actually today to parse out like what's
real attraction what's not. Valuations
are really high. This is why the big
firms do well. I actually think they can
wait or they have enough relative
certainty in the next round then lead
that round. But even then there isn't a
lot of certainty. When you guys did
cursor I don't think there was a lot of
certainty. And how many for how many
months were people saying cursor is
dead?
>> Oh even the morning of the acquisition
announcement people were still saying
that cursor is dead. I'm like, they just
announced that they were going to be
acquired by SpaceX for 60.
>> Tell me if I'm wrong. 3 million AR, $400
million round or somewhere maybe around
there.
>> Yeah. Something like that. Yeah.
>> Like a lot of people would say like
that's crazy. Why did they do that deal?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Well, look.
Okay. So, like founder judgment is a
very important thing, right? And so, you
know, getting to know founders over
time, spending a lot of time with them,
seeing how they think, like I'd like to
think that, you know, especially my
early stage partners are pretty good at
that. Um, secondly, like it is hard to
parse out real verse, you know, kind of
misleading attraction. And misleading in
the sense that like you can't take
market signal from it. Not that
anybody's doing any misleading. Um,
>> there's probably some of that too.
>> Yeah, there's probably some of that too,
but like I go back to
>> I love every now and then people are
like helping to redefine what AR
actually means. I'm like this is a very
helpful PSA for the
>> This is always helpful. Yes. Uh, yeah.
But like I don't know, come back to, you
know, is the market demanding more of
your product? Like that is always the
question. That's post a note on my on my
computer screen. Like
>> how do you know that when the company's
been only operating or selling for a
couple of months?
>> You're not going to be able to do it
with financial analysis. You'll have to
do it by really understanding the
customers, talking to the customers. And
then, you know, it's like one of the
things that I said about Harvey overtime
as an example, right? Um they did a
really good job commercially early days
like cuz they were they were smart. They
were re there was like a research plus
lawyer combo. um you know they got some
momentum and some and some you know
high-profile law firms to sign up early
days um but you know the usage was not
very good right and so like if you
looked at the actual deployment of it
just it looked like mediocre compared to
some other software firms um you know
and AI
>> from a retention standpoint
>> not retention no
usage of it um
>> now fast forward post reasoning models
like that totally flipped
>> and uh you could see you absolute
takeoff of adoption, right? And so a
bunch of different things happened at
the same time. Lawyers got way more
value out of the product. You could see
it in usage and engagement. Um, and then
it became because it was like high
utility usage and engagement. It almost
became a flip from what was previously
like, oh, we're scared of things like
hallucinations to, no, no, no, every
client is actually demanding the law
firms use the product. Um, and so, you
know, I think we look for markets like
that. We try to catch them early, like
we try to catch them earlier than when
than we did at Harvey. Um, but, you
know, that's the kind of signal that we
look for. You got to go you got to go
lay it down. Like, everyone can do
cohort analysis. Everyone can look at
renewal data. Um, but like understanding
the texture of the market and what the
customers actually want and need in
their alternatives. I think, you know,
that's how you make the decision. That's
why it's so important to have the early
stage business. Um, because they're the
deepest in the in the technology, in the
products. Um, and they, you know, they
obviously saw it in cursor and they've
seen it in many other things.
>> Jen, what's the biggest push back? I
mean, you're the most prolific
fundraiser I know. So, what's the push
back you get from
>> You could be very gainfully employed at
this firm.
>> I I agree that you are a prolific
fundraiser.
>> Um, what's the biggest push back you're
getting from LPs on like the state of
AI, the state of venture?
>> So, a lot of it is is worries around um,
you know, are we catching a falling
knife here? Just like the timing of the
market, where we are, like are things
overheated, etc. And so we talked a lot
about this at the the outset, you know,
around valuations and what the potential
of the market is, but I do get a lot of
sentiment from the LPs that their job is
also about to fundamentally change as
well. And and you mentioned earlier one
aspect of it around AI making it more
challenging to evaluate opportunities
and funds, but the other aspect of it as
well is the the LP historically has not
been incentivized to actually embrace
change in some respects, right? you
know, this is very much a job where um
the end goal is actually somewhat
diametrically opposed with the risk
tolerance of the GP and and this is just
the the mechanics of the industry, but I
often times say, you know, a GP can get
fired for missing out, you know, the
next, you know, Facebook, the next Uber,
right? Like that is the error of
omission and like that is fireable.
>> But LPs on the flip side only get fired
if you invest into Amanda. So in some
respects like the incentive outcomes are
actually completely opposite of the
>> you don't get fired for investing in IBM
if you're an LP.
>> Exactly. Yeah. And in fact like you
don't potentially even get fired for not
investing at all.
>> Yeah.
>> And so
>> if you miss if you miss the frontier
models back to your first question as an
LP but you kind of are along the
benchmark. Right.
>> Maybe slightly below the benchmark
you're keeping your job.
>> Right. Right. And that's fascinating.
>> And and also for most folks and I'll
leave fund of funds out of the the
equation because it's a different
different piece, but but you know for a
lot of folks the upside actually is not
that interesting for them. So the pitch
of like hey you're going to miss out on
the next potential generation incentive
misalignment.
>> It's it's actually quite um direct. So
so where do we go from there in terms of
the LP kind of role and see like it I
think we also have an important role and
function. And we oftent times talk about
in the context of our job as a leader of
the venture capital industry is we have
to help folks understand where the
future is going. And part of that is
understanding how to infiltrate not just
within their venture capital allocation
but across their entire portfolio. And
that I think is way more interesting
than just saying hey like you might miss
out on this next generation returns or
the optimization of like the next
frontier model or you know one or two
power law companies etc.
>> Access selection sizing is what LPs do.
So access
>> you could argue you have the data to
figure out who has done well
historically
>> out of those 20 firms out of 3,000 like
you are not going to see consistency
right maybe half of them are consistent
>> but the LP's job is also to find the
nextg firms as well as continue
accessing that so one is you access two
is selection three is portfolio
construction sizing and it's critical
from an LP standpoint
>> because if you have an asset class where
20 firms out of 3,000 do well you should
concentrate in those 15 20 firms pretty
consistently. So when I see a portfolio
with 50 60 70 venture capital firms,
it's very hard for me to imagine that
the overall portfolio can generate
better than the average.
>> And again, I'm going back to the average
in venture. That's just not what one
>> not compelling enough for the liquidity
>> relative to any of the other asset
classes, public markets, private equity.
I mean, private equity can probably get
you like one and a half to 2x net
without the lock up, without the risk
you're taking in. You talked about 60%
loss ratio. P doesn't have that,
>> right? Uh P has other problems we can
talk about today when it comes to AI
software, but um so portfolio
construction sizing for an LP is
critical. Like I've seen too many times
>> an LP or an allocator find an
interesting fund, actually get it right
>> and put 1% of their fund into it.
>> Great. You 10xed it. It returns 10% of
your fund. It does not move the needle
at all.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Where do you all
think we are today in that evolution
that Jen was talking about of how you
would I know you're biased, but the
appropriate
percentage of overall capital allocated
to venture and growth compared to
private equity or public markets or real
assets, credit, whatever it
>> Yeah, this is the this is hard for me to
answer because all I do is venture
growth. So, I would be biased to say
it's should be superersized. Um,
>> we like that answer though.
Look, look at the public markets today.
We vibe coded like something that
created a great way for us to assess AI
resiliency of public companies and now
we're doing that on the private side and
it's helping us hugely in in our growth
equity portfolio. But the in the SAS
public markets there only like 15 to 20
companies max trading above 10 times
revenues which is by an insane number
because it used to be dozens and dozens
a few years ago. And every one of those
companies for the most part is showing
acceleration of growth from AI. you're
either in monitoring, security,
deployment of agents, etc. So, it goes
back to the same principle where if you
are in some shape or form tied to AI,
which is the fastest growing facet of
all the elements of the GDP, then you
should superersize it in your portfolio.
That will have impacts in the public
markets. Even private equity today, when
they're doing a new investment, they're
looking for something that's AI native.
They're not looking to buy a workflow
software company growing 10% that's
seedbased. Like, that's just not
happening. They're looking for the
system of record. that can show
acceleration with an AI native
management team.
>> Yeah.
>> So that connective tissue of AI is
actually across every asset class today.
>> Yeah.
>> And the one of the strongest way to play
it is I mean it's it's probably through
venture.
>> Yeah.
>> But that's where selection access and
portfolio construction is really
critical.
>> Yeah. Well, even the exits though we
were talking about um you know Silverl
potentially you know buying workday for
example just like doing more provocative
things for example in private equity
land when you have the capabilities to
potentially infuse and and bring them
into into the future as a part of that.
The other version of it is also exits in
venture now way exceed private equity.
Like I you know like I was looking this
up last night. Private equity this year.
The biggest exits are um the buyout of
EA which was like around 50 billion and
Medline which is around 50 billion.
Curser let's not let's exclude the IPOs.
Like cursor was the M&A sale to SpaceX
was way bigger than that. And so the pro
the problem with that is like
>> you look at the pre-hat GPT vintages and
private equity
>> you would have paid I don't know 15 to
20 times EBIDA for an software asset
that's growing 10 20% max
>> y
>> if you look at the public markets today
that asset is trading at two times
revenue
>> y
>> and the problem is not that just the
valuation there might not be a buyer for
that company because
>> if you're looking at a software company
today the first thing you think about
what is the terminal value is it
resilient from AI. The best way to show
that is organic growth acceleration. Our
data shows 1 percentage of growth in the
public markets is equivalent to three
percentages of IBIDA.
>> Yep.
>> So, by the way, it's funny because in co
everyone was like we need to be
profitable. It was the inverse and now
it's the opposite.
>> No, no. 21 it was the inverse. Post it's
basically like fully uh aligned with
risk, right? Correlated with like risk
in the public.
>> Exactly. Um so, unfortunately, a lot of
those private equity deals, they're not
growing fast enough. they're not showing
that acceleration and they may not have
the management teams to revamp the
business like what intercom did is a
great example. Bring the founder bank uh
back, revamp the whole business, create
an AI native product, scale it, and then
sell. Like it's almost like you're
suiciding your existing business, which
in private equity is really hard to do.
>> It's really hard to do. I just spent a
little time with the founder uh and uh I
I went up to him at an event and I was
like I just gave him a big high five and
I'm like, "You did it, man.
>> You did. This is the this is the thing
that like is really really hard to do.
You know, it's an end of one right now.
>> Um but you know, there's a bunch of
really good founders who are capable
with those businesses, public markets,
private markets,
>> uh who I think are are going to take a
crack at it. Um so we'll see.
>> Yeah. May maybe on that thread though,
DJ, because we we also sometimes get the
push back as well like for folks who
have been in venture and allocated to
venture, they might also have a similar
problem where they do have the legacy
SAS businesses also as well. like what's
the balance between how you think about
the historical stuff?
>> Let me ask you that question. So, I'm
going to piggyback off of Jim's question
to you. You got a pick a 2016 through
2021 pre-Cat GPT vintage software
company that was fine but doesn't have
that AI native features anymore. It's
not accelerating. It's growing like 30%.
On the venture books, it's at like 10 20
times revenue.
It's not can go public anymore. Like no
one cares to take that public.
>> Yeah. Silver Lake has no interest in
that company anymore. They would have a
year ago. They don't.
>> Yeah.
>> What happens to that company?
>> Um, you know, look, it's like
>> we have a lot of exposure to those
companies, too. So,
>> I would say it's like it's it's very
TVD, right? Like I, you know, I was with
um one of our CEO founders this weekend
and, you know, he was like,
>> you know, give me the straight scoop.
Like, what do you actually think is
happening? And, um, you know, not don't
give me a he actually said to me, don't
give me a podcast answer. Um, which is
ironic. Um and you know I think both
things can be true that AI is like the
biggest generational change that we've
ever seen and it's going to transform
industries and also there will be some
enduring value of software companies
that are able to adapt right um part of
the thing that we're monitoring which
makes us extremely bullish about AI is
just actual diffusion into the real
economy right so coding I think if if
you were to paint the the bullish
scenario for regular software and for
slower pace of change, you would say um
you know coding hit but that's kind of a
head fake, right? Like coding coding is
perfectly documented, right? So it has
like perfect data uh it's verifiable and
it's simulatable, right? And so um like
most tasks in business do not share
those three attributes and so you know
maybe the diffusion into other knowledge
work beyond you know coding will take a
lot longer. That would be the case to
make for the software companies. Um, and
then some of them will evolve and and
have AI, you know, solutions and they'll
change their business models. Um, and I
think that's a must. Um, but that would
be the case for why maybe, you know,
it's a little bit overblown. I think if
you look at the way that a lot of the
public SAS companies have reacted over
the last few months, like that's I think
there's a little bit of a growing
realization in that. Um, all that makes
me super super super bullish on AI
though, right? So like if you look at
our portfolio um you know we have some
of those companies but about 95% of our
NAV is not in those companies right like
right there it's it's in the it's in the
companies that are you know growing very
fast accelerating etc. Um you know the
average I think it was the median
company in the US is spending $12 per
employee on AI per month. The top 1% of
the data set that we've seen is spending
$7,000
>> Wow. per employee on AI per month. So um
not only have we had like limited
diffusion beyond coding, but if you just
look at diffusion of, you know, the
shape of who is consuming tokens and
actually getting real value out of AI
today, we're super early, right? Like
banks, you know, the most cutting edge
banks are probably doing 1% of headcount
cost on on AI tools. Um and so the
reason this makes me very bullish is
these are the fastest growing companies
we've ever seen, like of all time.
Again, they're adding more revenue per
month than the than the mega cap tech
companies. Um, and yet it's probably on
the back of adoption of like 10 million
users, maybe 20, maybe 30 max. And you
know, there's one and a half billion
dollar workers in the US. And I think
it's going to transform the way we do a
lot of work.
>> Yeah, Kalpers's famously uh lost out on
billions of gains by not investing in
their back. They're making up for loss
time now. they they've uh converted
their portfolio from 91% to 58 and
venture and growth from 9 to 43. There's
probably some balance in between those
things. Uh but you know, they're they're
leaning hard into um but there's going
to be a lot of value still that's going
to be accreted in some of these
historical companies. And you I was sort
of joking around about bending. That was
probably a great outcome for Air Table.
You know, outside of the fact that, you
know, they're going to actually
>> spin off the hyper agent piece of the
business and actually um I think do
really interesting things with that. But
in the scheme of things, I think there's
going to be a lot of homes for a lot of
things. And this zero sum thinking I
think is is probably the pitfall of
which we would would advise against.
>> So we talked about um we've talked about
you know venture growth, we've talked
about private equity, you know we've
talked about um public markets. Um and
by the way the composition of all of
those have like radically changed over
the last 10 years. Um we also have had
the emergence of entirely new categories
that are available in the private
markets like private credit. Um do you
have a view on sort of outlook of those
on a relative basis
>> in software in particular?
>> Yeah, I'd say in technology
>> uh the vantage point we have is looking
at private credit which resides in a lot
of private equity software portfolios
which is hundreds of billions.
>> Mhm.
>> I'll give you one statistic. So you look
at 2122
about 2 to 300 billion in LBO software
transactions happened with over 200
billion in debt taken out. The average
valuation for those software deals over
25 to 32 times IBIDA. Those companies
today are worth probably half that. The
reason you're seeing redemptions in the
credit markets in private credit is
exactly that. They're looking at the
public markets. You've had CS
apocalypse. It's been a massive
correction in software and the val and
you can see a contraction in valuations
which means the leverage ratios have
gone up dramatically. So
if you are a software company that is in
somewhat not resilient to AI I think
you're challenged both in terms of your
equity position also credit as well.
>> By the way even the um AI version of
private equity is not completely
insulated. We oftentimes talk about like
you know just because you put Sears on a
website didn't make it Amazon right you
have to have the benefit of building
Amazon from the studs logistically to
make it Amazon. It's not just the
website and in a lot of instances with
the private equity backed companies that
are now just infusing AI. We've seen it
actually in some of our companies as
well where the peer competitor is like
oh the first thing I'll do is of course
hire AI customer service agents because
that's like an easy lowhanging fruit.
Like turns out if you don't actually
build in the workflow, you start to turn
customers very quickly if they're used
to talking to a human and for every
dollar uh every drop in NPS is like a
direct correlation with drop in revenue
and then you start to spiral especially
if you have debt ladened on top of it.
So oftentimes uh sometimes we hear from
folks like well I'll just do the AI you
know kind of version of private equity.
It's not a pan panacea for for
generating returns especially when it's
just so categorically different from a
technological perspective to actually
infuse that throughout the company as
well.
>> Yeah, you can't just throw an operating
partner at the company and say let's put
AI on it. It just doesn't work.
>> You need to completely and if you have
by the way if you do have a founder
mentality at the management team like it
is possible but the board has to be
aligned the all the investors have to be
aligned
>> and you do have to make some really hard
decisions the way intercom did.
>> Yeah. Yep.
>> Yeah. So obviously this is a group that
is very pro you know venture and growth
this category. Um let's talk about the
legitimate opposition to it and what is
the case you know for why maybe the you
know the risk that you're taking or
whatever it may be with venture and
growth you know doesn't justify it.
>> Uh I mean the push back we get a lot is
timeline to liquidity. So it takes the
average unicorn is private for 10 plus
years typically and then you got all
these follow on rounds that are
happening pretty quickly one after the
other. You see maybe the same logo in
five six different firms
>> and the question is how do you get out
of it
>> um and so
>> and an IPO isn't actually a
distribution.
>> It takes it could take 12 24 plus months
before you actually get liquidity out of
an IPO. like especially if you own 10
15% at IPO like it's going to take a
long time if you're in the generational
company. So we get that push back a lot
in terms of timeline to liquidity.
>> Mhm. And then um what is the what is the
sort of counter to that push back?
>> Well counter to that push back is going
back to 3,000 firms 20 do well
consistently. If you're in the top 1% of
those firms and you have a category
winner you want to make sure that
compounds actually.
>> Yeah. Um would you have wanted to sell
stripe data bricks or any of those other
companies three four years ago? Like the
answer is unanimously no. Uh now could
some of these companies go public
earlier than not? Sure. Entropic was
really first funded in 2021. It's about
to go public 5 years later.
>> Yeah.
>> Cursor from first acquisition from first
financing to acquisition is short. Like
>> so the best venture firms actually have
fund returning liquidity pretty quickly
maybe even quicker than private equity.
But that subset of firms is tiny.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yep. Actually, very famously uh a
year and a half ago or so, we went to
our fund one LPs. At that point in time,
the fund one was 16 years old and we had
this position in Stripe that we invested
at the seed stage and we asked all of
our LPs like, "Hey, do you want
liquidity out on this?" We recognized,
you know, the job that we came to do is
now done 16 years in. Like, do you want
liquidity back on this? And every single
one of those LPs said, "No, we'd rather
let this continue to compound." And then
ultimately a year later, you know, we
decided to to make that exit because
it's 17 years in. We've got to get this
this liquidity out. We got to wrap up
the fund, etc. But, you know, so many
LPS, I think, is very specific to
certain categories, right? Endowments
would prefer to let it run. Family
offices, quite frankly, don't want the
money back because they don't want to
pay taxes on it. They'd rather have it
continue to compound. And so there is
specific nuance with each LP group where
it's very hard to paint a broad brush
stroke stroke on like across the board
on everyone wanting the same thing. But
I also think to your point
>> the very best LPS, excuse me, the very
best GPS have manufactured along the way
liquidity and particularly in 2021 when
a lot of folks didn't take money off the
table. You know, I think that was a good
sign of the first indicator and now in
this next cycle, it's can you actually
get some early liquidity out through M&A
and then let you know, potentially the
winners IPO over time with the fullness
of of compounding as well.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> I'm going to end on this note because I
I thought this is an interesting
question that you and Gavin were were uh
tossing back and forth DG on. Um he he
uh didn't want to answer the question on
what will be the next $10 trillion
company, but he had certainty around
what will be the next 20 trillion market
cap company. So, I'm going to ask both
of you, uh, what do you think is going
to be the next, uh, hundred trillion
dollar market cap?
>> Oh my gosh, here we go. I can't even
think in those things.
>> Yeah, we're, uh, that's probably two two
tech cycles away, not just one. Uh, it
is possible that we have entirely new
companies that get created. And I think
a lot of the market cap creation that
you would talk about that would drive a
10 trillion outcome or more um, is in
new product areas that haven't yet been
touched, right? So
>> yeah,
>> like what I talked about the sort of
diffusion of the technology into the
enterprise like we're nowhere, right?
>> Um,
>> you know, a year ago everyone talked
about consumer all the time. No one even
talks about consumer AI anymore. But
that is going to like the end use case
for consumers is not going to be a
chatbot interface. Like that's the
skumorphic version. We're going to have
a native version. It's going to be
proactive. It's going to do work on our
behalf. It's going to it's going to
create a ton of value for for consumers.
And we're kind of nowhere on that. I
mean, yeah, there's, you know, a billion
chat users, but, you know, like we're
that's like scratching the surface. Um,
we are, um, nowhere on robotics, but I
think robotics is going to be bigger
than the language stuff. Um, and I think
it's going to happen in the next 10
years.
>> Um, we are almost nowhere on autonomy,
right? Like there's fewer than 10,000
Whimos uh, live in the US, way fewer
robo taxis. Um, and then, you know, a
lot of open space for others to build in
that area, too. Um, we, you know,
healthcare is 18% of GDP. Yeah.
>> Like we, we've, we've done nothing to
scratch the surface either on care
delivery or on drug discovery yet. I
mean, there's some companies that are
working on it, showing some early signs
of progress, but I think the progress
that we make there in the next 10 years
is going to be massive. Um, and then,
you know, we're in this interesting era
of reimagining, um, all things physical
world from defense to manufacturing to
data centers. Um, and so I look at the
confluence of all these trends and I'm
like, yeah, it may feel like we've, you
know, we've we've done a lot with AI
already. Um, but 10 years from now,
we're going to look back and say, oh my
gosh, like those other major areas
created a ton of value.
>> Um, and so I'm excited that I think the
next SpaceX AI or OpenAI are probably
going to get created. Um, and they'll
probably be in those kinds of domains.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I'll add one category that to me
is both a concern but a huge
opportunity. It's a plug for your new
fund on the on the opportunities fund
that you did. I think very
simplistically about like the bottleneck
in AI today. It's not demand, it's on
the supply side. So you got energy, the
grid data center, then you got chips,
then you got frontier models and apps.
The US is amazing at the right side of
that. So like chips and onwards. The VC
ecosystem supports that well. Um I think
the new fund you have is really going to
help on the left side as well because
the US doesn't have a problem with
energy generation. It has a problem with
speed to power.
>> Yeah.
>> That's permissioning transmission.
That's regulatory. Other countries are
putting out 10x more renewable capacity
a year.
>> So that is a real bottleneck and that
means reimagining the data center. You
talked about the density being 10x plus.
Well, you can't just repurpose an old
data center for the for new AI facility.
So this is where the new fund you have
can create not 10 50 but 100 billion
plus opportunities as well that can
really solve the bottleneck and I think
that is a real concern because demand is
not the concern. Um, a lot of I've heard
LP say this is like the dotcom or this
is co. It's not because the traction is
real and it's not ephemeral revenue like
>> co
>> the bottleneck could be supply but if
you have the right inputs like the fund
that's you're now backing those
companies next generation chip companies
memory etc. That's a huge opportunity.
>> It's time for machine age. Let's bring
the machines.
>> I love it.
>> All right let's close on that. Thank you
both so much. It was super fun. Thank
you for having us. Awesome. See you.